positiveparentingsolutions.com 2018-10-20

# Privacy Policy - Positive Parenting Solutions Positive Parenting Solutions

**Last updated: October 18, 2018**

Welcome to positiveparentingsolutions.com (the “ **Site** ”). At Positive Parenting Solutions (“ **PPS** ”), we are committed to respecting your privacy and to protecting any information you provide to us. Accordingly, our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, process, use, and disclose the personal information you provide us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using the Site or otherwise interacting with us 

The Privacy Policy is a part of, and subject to, the Site’s Terms and Conditions. The Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions are legally binding on all users of the Site. Please be sure to read this entire Privacy Policy and our Terms and Conditions carefully before using or submitting information to the Site or otherwise providing us with your personal information. 

By accessing or using the Site, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions. If you do not consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy, do not use our services, access the Site, or provide us with any information. 

These practices may be changed, but any changes will be posted and changes will only apply to activities and information on a going forward, not retroactive basis. You are encouraged to review the Privacy Policy whenever you visit the Site to make sure that you understand how any information you provide will be used. 

  1. **Collection of Information**  
We collect personally identifiable information you provide to us (“ **Personal Information** ”). For example, we collect your name, and email address when you create a purchase account, subscribe to our newsletter, register for a webinar, or respond to a survey. If you place an order via the Site, we will also collect your mailing address, phone number and credit card information. We never sell your information to any other company or agency. Below, we describe more specifically how we collect your information and what we do with it. 
    1. **Information You Give to Us.**
      1. **Information that is necessary for the use of the Site and our services.** We ask for and collect the following personal information about you when you use the Site and/or services. This information is necessary for the adequate performance of the contract between you and us and to allow us to comply with our legal obligations. Without it, we may not be able to provide you with all the requested services.
      2. **Account Information.** When you create a purchase account, subscribe to our newsletter, register for a webinar, or respond to a survey we require certain information such as your first name, last name, and email address.
      3. **Purchase Information.** When you place an order via the Site, we will also collect your mailing address, phone number and credit card information.
      4. **Communications with PPS.** When you communicate with PPS, we collect information about your communication and any information you choose to provide.
      5. **Information you choose to give us.** Other than what is described above, you may choose to provide us with additional information in order to obtain a better user experience when using the Site or our services. This additional information will be processed based on your consent.
    2. **Information We Automatically Collect from Your Use of the Site or Subscription Service.**  
We automatically collect information, including personal information, about the services you use and how you use them. This information is necessary for the adequate performance of the contract between you and us, to enable us to comply with legal obligations and given our legitimate interest in being able to provide and improve the functionalities of the Site and our services. 
      1. **Anonymous Information.** As you navigate through the Site, we may collect and store anonymous information (“ **Anonymous Information** ”) about you using various technologies such as cookies, Internet tags, advertising pixels, and navigational data. Your browser automatically transmits some of this information to us, such as the URL of the website you just visited, the browser version your computer is operating, the date and time you visited, the pages you visited on the Site, and your IP address, and we may store that information. 
        1. **“Cookies”** Cookies are tiny alphanumeric identifiers that are stored on your computer and allow us to adjust the Site to meet your personal browsing preferences. If your browser is set to refuse cookies, you may not have access to all areas or features of the Site.
    3. **Information We Collect from Third Parties.** We may collect information, including personal information, that others provide about you, or obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect. We do not control, supervise, or respond for how the third parties providing your information process your personal data, and any information request regarding the disclosure of your personal information to us should be directed to such third parties. 
      1. **Third Party Services.** If you link, connect, or login with a third party service (e.g. Google, Facebook, WeChat), the third party service may send us information such as your registration and profile information from that service. This information varies and is controlled by that service or as authorized by you via your privacy settings at that service. 
    4. **Other Sources.** To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may receive additional information about you, such as demographic data or fraud detection information, from third party service providers and/or partners, and combine it with information we have about you. For example, we may receive background check results (with your consent where required) or fraud warnings from service providers like identity verification services for our fraud prevention and risk assessment efforts
  2. **Use of Your Information**
    1. **Anonymous Information.** We may aggregate, evaluate, and use Anonymous Information to improve the Site and our business, and we may provide it to third parties. We may use cookies, IP addresses, or other Anonymous Information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track customer website navigation, gather broad demographic information, and make the Site better for you.
    2. **Personal Information.** Gathering Personal Information about our users allows us to serve you better. We will never use your Personal Information in a way that is prohibited by applicable law. Here are some ways in which we might use your Personal Information: 
      1. **Our Business Purposes.** We may use your Personal Information for our everyday business purposes, such as to process your orders, provide services to you, to communicate information and updates to you, and to update our profile about you.
  3. **Sharing Your Information**
    1. **Compliance with Law, Responding to Legal Requests, Preventing Harm and Protection of Our Rights.** PPS may disclose your information, including personal information, to courts, law enforcement or governmental authorities, or authorized third parties, if and to the extent we are required or permitted to do so by law or if such disclosure is reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with our legal obligations; (ii) to comply with legal process and to respond to claims asserted against PPS; (iii) to respond to verified requests relating to a criminal investigation or alleged or suspected illegal activity or any other activity that may expose us, you, or any other of our users to legal liability; (iv) to enforce and administer our Terms & Conditions; or (v) to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of PPS, its employees, or members of the public. Where appropriate, we may notify you about legal requests unless: (i) providing notice is prohibited by the legal process itself, by court order we receive, or by applicable law; or (ii) we believe that providing notice would be futile, ineffective, create a risk of injury or bodily harm to an individual or group, or create or increase a risk of fraud upon PPS. 
    2. **Service Providers.** From time to time, we may employ companies and individuals to perform certain services on our behalf (such as conducting audits, performing legal services, processing credit card payments, or providing customer service). These third-party service providers may have access to Personal Information, but only to the extent required to perform their assigned roles, and they may not use your Personal Information for any other reas
    3. **Your Consent.** Where you have provided consent, we may share your information, including personal information, as described at the time of consent.
    4. **Ownership Transfer.** We may transfer any information, including your Personal Information, in the event of a transfer of ownership, assets, securities, or bankruptcy involving us and in connection with business transactions such as buying or selling subsidiaries or engaging in joint ventures with third parties; provided, however, that we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use any transferred information, including your Personal Information, in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. 
  4. **Your Rights  
**You may exercise any of the rights described in this section by contacting PPS through the contact information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy. Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request. 
    1. **Managing Your Information.** Through your account you can manage certain settings, such as to subscribe or unsubscribe to content. 
    2. **Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Information.** You have the right to ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal information concerning you. 
    3. **Data Access and Portability.** In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to request copies of your personal information held by us. You may also be entitled to request copies of personal information that you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format and/or request us to transmit this information to another service provider (where technically feasible). 
    4. **Data Retention and Erasure.** We generally retain your personal information for as long as is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and us, for our legitimate business interests, or to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your information you can request that we erase your personal information. Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information: 
      1. We may retain some of your personal information as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention and enhancing safety.
      2. We may retain and use your personal information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations.
      3. Some copies of your information (e.g., log records) may remain in our database, but are disassociated from personal identifiers.
      4. Residual copies of your personal information may not be removed from our backup systems for a limited period of time.
    5. **Withdrawing Consent and Restriction of Processing.** Where you have provided your consent to the processing of your personal information by PPS you may withdraw your consent at any time by changing your Account Settings or by sending a communication to PPS specifying which consent you are withdrawing. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of any processing activities based on such consent before its withdrawal. Additionally, in some jurisdictions, applicable law may give you the right to limit the ways in which we use your personal information, in particular where (i) you contest the accuracy of your personal information; (ii) the processing is unlawful and you oppose the erasure of your personal information; (iii) we no longer need your personal information for the purposes of the processing, but you require the information for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; or (iv) you have objected to the processing and pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of PPS override your own. 
    6. **Objection to Processing.** In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to require PPS not to process your personal information for certain specific purposes (including profiling) where such processing is based on legitimate interest. If you object to such processing, PPS will no longer process your personal information for these purposes unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for such processing or such processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. 

Where your personal information is processed for direct marketing purposes, you may, at any time, ask PPS to cease processing your data for these direct marketing purposes. 

    7. **Lodging Complaints.** You have the right to lodge complaints about the data processing activities carried out by PPS before the competent data protection authorities. 
  5. **Protection of Your Information** To prevent unauthorized access to, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. However, no security system is perfect, and we cannot guarantee that information you provide to us over the Internet will remain private. We also cannot guarantee that information you transmit to us over the Internet will not be intercepted. 
  6. **Use of Site by Children** The Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. We will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information via the Site from visitors in this age group and will take prompt steps to delete any such personally identifiable information.
  7. **Tracking** At this time, the Site does not respond to web browser “do not track” signals. We may add this functionality in the future, and if we do, we will update this Privacy Policy to let you know. For now, third parties may collect personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use our Site. 
  8. **California & Vermont Residents. **PPS will not share information it collects about you with its affiliates or third parties (both financial and non-financial), except as required or permitted by your state’s law. 
  9. **For California Users Only  
**California Civil Code Section 1798.83 requires certain businesses to disclose, upon a written request, (i) a list of the kinds of personal information that the business has disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, and (ii) the names and addresses of all of the third parties that received personal information from the business for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. Businesses must respond to such requests within 30 days, but they are only obligated to respond to one request from a customer in a calendar year. 

If you live in California, you may request this disclosure by sending an e-mail request to: [ administration@PositiveParentingSolutions.com ](mailto:administration@PositiveParentingSolutions.com) listing your name, address, and e-mail address. You must also specifically indicate the nature of your request by including the following language or language substantially similar to it: “I request that you send me your third-party information sharing disclosures as required by California Civil Code Section 1798.83.” Alternatively, you may mail your request to the following address: Positive Parenting Solutions, Inc., 1132 Weeping Glen Court, Raleigh, NC 27614. 

  10. **Changes to this Privacy Policy** The Internet is constantly changing, as is the nature of our Internet business operations, so we will likely need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes to this Privacy Policy, we will post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site and update the “Last Updated” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. We will also provide you with notice of the modification by email at least thirty (30) days before the date it becomes effective. You should check this Privacy Policy frequently to review the latest version of the Privacy Policy. Our posting an amended version of the Privacy Policy on the Site will serve as notice to you of that amendment. Your continued access to or use of the Site and/or our services will be subject to the revised Privacy Policy. If you disagree with the revised Privacy Policy, you may cancel our services and refrain from access and use of the Site. 

**  
How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions, requests, or concerns related to this Privacy Policy:   
Email: [administration@positiveparentingsolutions.com](mailto:administration@positiveparentingsolutions.com)  
Phone: 1-800-604-1092
